Let's learn about the deck.
Deck or double ended cue is a type of cue in which insertion and removal of elements can either be performed
from the front or their ear.
Thus, it does not follow fee for rule, first in, first out.
So this is the insertion and removal from the rear and from the front insertion and removal so it can
either be performed from the front or the rear.
We have types of deck, the input restricted deck and this deck input is restricted.
F is single and but allows deletion at both the ends or the output restricted deck in this deck.
Output is restricted as at the single end, but allows insertion at both the end.
OK, so.
This is that deck, this is we we we need to know that we can insert and remove both from here and from
the front sides sides.
Back operation in a circular array.
If the array is full, we start from the beginning.
But in a linear array implementation, if the array is full gnome, no more elements can be inserted
in each of the operation below.
If the array is full, overflow message is thrown before performing the following operations.
These steps are followed take can array deck of the size and then set two pointers at the first position
and set front minus one and three is equal to zero.
So this is the basics of the deck operation that we are going to deal with in the next videos, and
we will start by making the front minus one and the rear equal to zero, so.
In the next video, we are going to talk about that deck insertion and we will see how we will.